# **Leonard Harris**

# Senior/Lead Software Developer

Results-focused **Senior Software Developer** with 6+ years experience having successfully developed & deployed complex mobile applications and web API's. Strong problem solver capable of **leading projects through all development stages** under pressure. Delivering **smart**, **intuitive and user friendly software solutions** with the latest cutting edge technology and best development practices. Good understanding of UX/UI principles with design experience in Figma and FluidUI.

#### Contact

#### **Address**

New Zealand, TKI, 1010

#### **Phone**

+64 27 872 0215

#### E-mail

leojharris@hotmail.com

#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/leonardjharris

## Skills

Xamarin	Excellent
.NET	Very Good
MVVM	Very Good
Minimal API	Very Good
UITesting	Very Good

# **Work History**

#### 2022-04 -Current

## Contract Software Developer

Specific Solutions (NZ) Limited, Tauranga, BOP

- Upgraded software to improve flexibility & performance.
- Developed Minimal API project deployed to AWS using RDS fully manage cloud database service.

## 2020-12 -Current

## C# Software Engineer (Xamarin)

Remote, Modeus Pty Ltd

- Healthcare software
- SaaS Mobile Solutions
- Lead large enterprise scale projects from requirement gathering, design, development,
   QA to app store deployment.
- Produced new design and development user guides to assist other team members.
- Managed design operation with Figma

#### 2018-03 -2020-10

## C# Software Engineer (Xamarin)

Remote, Xenia Suite

- Hotel Management Software
- RESTful services
- Developed 4 robust mobile applications

**UITesting** Very Good Figma UI/UX Very Good Android (Android Good Studio) SQL Server Good IOS (Xcode) Average Azure Average **AWS** Average

## Software

Microsoft

Visual Studio
Community
2019

SQL Server
Management
Studio

Visual Studio
Team Services

Android

Very Good

Very Good

Average

Average

## Languages

Studio

English Excellent

- SaaS Mobile Solutions
- Supervised University Intern
- UI/UX
- Unit Testing & Xamarin.UITest

2016-03 -2018-03

## C# Software Engineer (Xamarin)

Office/Remote, Efinity Digital

- Oil and Gas logistics software
- SaaS Mobile Solutions
- RESTful services

2014-01 -Current

## **University of Waikato**

Student Ambassador

- Enthusiastically and proactively represented the University of Waikato as a Student Ambassador and multiple class representative positions
- Proven communication skills in one-on-one and group setting while delegating tasks
- Lead, organized and mobilized diverse groups in projects.

## **Education**

2012-03 -2015-06 University of Waikato, Hamilton, Bachelor of Computer Science

- A- average for 300 level papers (final year).
- Awarded 'Best Team' medal in a 200 level
   Software Engineering paper for Spearheading and directing a group of 5.
- Student Committee Member of the Admissions Appeals Committee.
- Undergraduate Student Member of the Board of Faculty.
- Multiple Student Class Representative Positions.

## **Commercial Projects**

**2021-01** Chemist Warehouse App

**2021-01** DoseLink

2020-01	Maintenance
2019-01	Xenia Room
2019-01	Housekeeping
2019-01	Minibar
2018-01	Sales Order Entry
2018-01	Xenia Guest
2017-01	Trackit Education
2017-01	Inventory Management
2016-01	Taranaki Rugby Football Union App
2016-01	My Trackit

# **Personal Projects**

ScanZap - Coming Soon - Jan 2021 Sussed - Coming Soon - Jan 2021 Spinit - Android - Jan 2018 -Amplified Scheduler - Jan 2015 Kiwi Sports Tracker - Jan 2014

## **Volunteer Activities**

2016-01 - Current	Startup Weekend Taranaki
	Self
	<ul> <li>Winner team of the 2016 Taranaki Startup</li> </ul>
	<u>Competition</u>
2013-01 -	University of Waikato
Current	Undergraduate Board of Faculty Representative

2014-01 - Committee Student Member

2015-01	University of Waikato, Admission Appeals Committee
2012-01 -	Totara Springs
2015-01	Leader / Support Leader

crafts etc.

Strong communication and active listening skill

• Oversee children actively engaged in sports,

• Strong communication and active listening skills with leaders and children.

2012-01 - University of Waikato
2014-01 Student Class Representati

Student Class Representative Positions

## **Interests**

Surfing

Skiing

Playing guitar

Beekeeping

Contributing to great open source projects on GitHub!